<resources>
<string name="help_text" translation_description="Please do not change the &lt; and &gt; markup">
&lt;big&gt;&lt;b&gt;Sky Map for Android&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Version %s&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;https://github.com/sky-map-team/stardroid&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;b&gt;Introduction and Quick Start&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Sky Map is your catalog of the night sky! Point your Android-powered device up, and you will see a map of the brightest
stars, constellations, and planets in that part of the sky.&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;b&gt;Visible Layers&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Sky Map organizes the objects it shows you into layers.  Each layer can
be toggled using the on-screen controls.  The layers are:&lt;br/&gt;
      <span>&#8226;</span> Stars&lt;br/&gt;
      <span>&#8226;</span> Constellations&lt;br/&gt;
      <span>&#8226;</span> Messier Objects&lt;br/&gt;
      <span>&#8226;</span> Planets&lt;br/&gt;
      <span>&#8226;</span> Meteor Showers&lt;br/&gt;
      <span>&#8226;</span> Right Ascension and Declination Grid&lt;br/&gt;
      <span>&#8226;</span> Horizon and cardinal points&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
      
The brightest stars, constellations, and planets are labeled. 
Planets display as images that are larger than they will appear in the sky.
Sky Map may show objects that are above the horizon line (represented as a straight line)
that you may not be able to see, unless you live in an area that is flat and without buildings.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;b&gt;On-screen controls&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Tap on the screen to show the on-screen controls. On one side of the screen are
the toggles for the layers described above.  They are orange when the layers are
enabled and white when disabled.&lt;br/&gt;

The other side of the screen has a toggle to switch between
automatic and manual mode.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Navigation Modes&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
When first installed Sky Map will be in Automatic Mode and will use the phone\'s sensors
to display a map of the sky in the direction your phone is pointing. By
switching into Manual Mode, you can drag the map with your finger to explore the
sky. You can also rotate the map with two fingers and use a pinch gesture to zoom in and out.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;b&gt;Search&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Sky Map helps answer the question \'What star is that?\' or \'Where is ...?\'
Access the search function through the phone\'s menu button or through the Quick Search Box directly on the
Desktop. Enter the name of the star, constellation, or planet you wish
to find, and Sky Map will list the matching search items. Select one
and Sky Map will display a targeting circle and an arrow prompting you where to point
the phone to find the object. The circle will change from blue to red, finally turning orange
when the object is within your field of view.&lt;br/&gt;
NOTE: If you are in Manual Mode, Sky Map will simply move the map to show you the object.&lt;br/&gt;
To exit Search Mode, tap the small cross in the corner of the screen.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;b&gt;Time Travel&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

Time Travel mode enables you to use Sky Map to see the sky at times
other than the present. Select \'Time Travel\' from the main menu, and
then select one of the Popular Dates or choose your own date and time
using the \'Change the Date\' and \'Change the Time\' dialogs. Selections
are restricted to the years 1900-2100 due to limitations on accuracy
caused mainly by the gravitational influence of Jupiter. When you\'re
done, press \'Go!\' to fly through time to your destination. Your Sky
Map is now in time travel mode, displaying the date you\'re visiting,
with controls for \'playing\' time forwards and backwards from here.
Click these buttons once to start moving slowly through time, and
several times to travel faster and faster.&lt;br/&gt;

Time Travel can be used to answer a variety of questions, including
\'What will I be able to see just after sunset this evening?\', \'When
will I next have a good chance of seeing Mercury?\', and \'According to
Hesiod, when should I harvest my grapes?\'&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;b&gt;Hubble Gallery&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Sky Map contains a gallery of images from the Hubble telescope.  Access the Gallery
by selecting the Gallery item in the menu.  Once inside the Gallery, you
can browse the available images by scrolling with your finger. If you tap
one of the thumbnail images, Sky Map shows you the full size image. If you
tap the Search button, Sky Map will switch to Search mode to find the object
matching the image.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;b&gt;Night Vision Mode&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Night Vision Mode is designed to protect your dark-adapted eyes.  When you
select the Night Vision menu option, Sky Map will display the map in a red
color, dim the screen and switch off the button backlights.
Select the option again to revert to normal colors.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;b&gt;Setting Your Location&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Sky Map needs your approximate location in order to show you the correct star
map.  By default, it will determine this from your cellular network.  If you are
out of range, or have network location disabled it will use your phone\'s GPS.
You can also set your location manually via the settings menu, either by
supplying a place name or as a latitude and longitude (in degrees.)  Note that
Sky Map requires a data connection to determine your latitude and longitude from
a place name.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;b&gt;Troubleshooting and Limitations&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;The map is inaccurate.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
If you find that the map does not accurately line up with the real sky there
could be a number of reasons:&lt;br/&gt;
1) Is your compass calibrated?  Try holding the phone and rotating your wrist in
figures of eight to calibrate it.  You may need to repeat this at intervals
- this is a feature of the phone, rather than Sky Map.&lt;br/&gt;
2) Does the application have an accurate fix on your location?  Is your GPS or
network location turned on?&lt;br/&gt;
3) Do you have the correct time and timezone set?
Sky Map needs to calculate Universal Time, and it needs your local time AND
timezone to do this.  If your device has a SIM card then these will usually be
set correctly.&lt;br/&gt;
4) Do you have magnetic correction switched on?  In some parts of the world the
difference between magnetic North and True North can be as much as 20 degrees.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;The map does not move&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Are you in manual mode?  If not, this could be due to an uncalibrated compass.
Follow the steps above to \'unstick\' it.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;b&gt;Credits&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Engineering, Design and Product Management&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Brent Bryan, Dominic Widdows, Hector Ouilhet, James Powell,
John Taylor, Kevin Serafini, Lior Ron&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;i&gt;Open Source Contributors&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Christopher Wilcox, PhD&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

&lt;b&gt;Acknowledgments&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Sky Map was originally developed as "Google Sky Map" by Google Inc. and open sourced
in 2012.
Sky Map uses maps derived from data from:&lt;br/&gt;
Centre de Donnees astronomiques de Strasbourg (http://cdsweb.u-strasbg.fr/)&lt;br/&gt;
The Bright Star Catalogue, 5th Revised Ed. (Hoffleit D., Warren Jr W.H.)&lt;br/&gt;
The HYG Database, HYG v1.0. (http://www.astronexus.com/)&lt;br/&gt;
History and Accurate Positions for the NGC/IC Objects (Harold G. Corwin Jr)&lt;br/&gt;
Revised New General Catalogue of Nonstellar Astronomical Objects
(Sulentic J.W., Tifft W.G.)&lt;br/&gt;
SFA Star Charts
(http://observe.phy.sfasu.edu/SFAStarCharts/SFAStarChartFAQ.html)&lt;br/&gt;
Positions of Solar System Objects are calculated from data provided by the USNO
(http://www.usno.navy.mil/USNO/astronomical-applications)&lt;br/&gt;
Spherical coverage data obtained from
(http://www2.research.att.com/~njas/coverings)&lt;br/&gt;
Hubble Images provided by NASA\'s Space Telescope Science Institute
(http://hubblesite.org/)&lt;br/&gt;
Meteor shower data from the International Meteor Organization
(http://www.imo.net/data)&lt;br/&gt;
M31 image by Peter Kennett (https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:M31(Kennett).jpg)&lt;br/&gt;
</string>
</resources>

